semrush.ru 2015-11-13

# SEMrush.com -> Privacy Policy

At SEMrush, we strive to develop innovative services to better serve our users. We recognize that privacy is an important issue, so we design and operate our services with the protection of your privacy in mind. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of information we gather when you use SEMrush services, as well as some of the steps we take to safeguard it.

PRIVACY POLICY

Our Privacy Policy explains what information we collect and why we collect it.   
How we use that information.  
The choices we offer, including how to access and update information.

Your privacy matters to SEMrush so whether you are new to SEMrush or a long time user, please do take the time to get to know our practices – and if you have any questions, please do not hesitate to contact us: **[MAIL@SEMRUSH.COM](mailto:mail@semrush.com)**

Our Policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting [semrush.com](http://www.semrush.com/) (and any associated sub-domains) (our sites), or taking out any form of subscription with us, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We collect information to provide better services to all of our users. SEMrush collects non-personally identifying information your browser makes available whenever you visit a website. This information includes your Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your query and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. We use this information to operate, develop and improve our services. Some of our services require your personal information in order to (typically your name, email address, credit card information, billing address, telephone, etc.) use that information to provide the service.

DESCRIPTION OF SERVICES

We use the information we collect from all of our services to provide, maintain, protect and improve them, to develop new ones, and to protect SEMrush and our users.

SEMrush provides users with access to a rich collection of resources, including but not limited to, accsess to online marketing platform and application program interfaces (API) for its use. You also understand that the Service may include certain communications from SEMrush, such as service announcements, administrative messages and that these communications are considered part of SEMrush free registration and paid subscriptions. Unless explicitly stated otherwise, any new features that augment or enhance the current Service, including the release of new SEMrush properties, SEMrush and 3rd related party marketing companies, shall be subject to this Agreement. You are responsible for obtaining access to the Service, and that access may involve third-party fees (such as Internet service provider or airtime charges). Additionally, you must provide and are responsible for all equipment necessary to access the Service.

INFORMATION WE SHARE

SEMrush does not share your personal information with third parties or public except our service providers, such as SMTP infrastructure providers and payment processors, resellers, performing services on our behalf. These service providers may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes.

Occasions when SEMrush will deem it necessary to release client information include but are not limited to:

  * when requested to do so by law enforcement agencies;
  * when obliged to do so under US law;
  * for the purpose of pursuing outstanding debts or liabilities;
  * when given permission to do so by said client.

We use analytics tools and other third party technologies, such as Google Analytics and etc. to collect non-personal information in the form of various usage and user metrics when you use our online service.

These tools and technologies collect and analyze certain types of information, including cookies, IP addresses, device and software identifiers, referring and exit URLs, onsite behavior and usage information, feature use metrics and statistics, usage and purchase history, and other similar information.

The third party analytics companies who collect information on our Service may combine the information collected with other information they have independently collected from other websites and/or other online or mobile products and services relating to your activities across their network of websites as well as online and/or mobile products and services. We use this information to operate, develop and improve our service.

Many of these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies.

We do not share personal information with companies, organizations and individuals outside of SEMrush unless one of the following circumstances applies:

We may share aggregated, nonpersonally identifiable information publicly and with our partners – like publishers, advertisers or connected sites. For example, we may share information publicly to show trends about the general use of our services.

If SEMrush is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of any personal information and give affected users notice before personal information is transferred or becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

You can object to the use of your personal data for commercial purpose at any time.

INFORMATION STORAGE

By submitting your personal information, you agree to it`s transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask that you do not share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via is internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try and prevent unauthorised access.

INFORMATION SECURITY

We work hard to protect SEMrush and our users from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of information we hold. We review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems.

We work hard to restrict access to personal information to SEMrush employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to process it for us, and who are subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.

To prevent being a phishing website victim, always check domain details when you are providing your personal information. Please, be aware that if you suspect the website you’re on is a fake semrush.com site, contact us directly.

WHEN THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES

Our Privacy Policy applies to all of the services offered by Semrush Inc. and its affiliates and services offered on other sites (such as our affiliate program - Berush).

Our Privacy Policy does not apply to services offered by other companies or individuals. Our Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of other companies and organizations who advertise our services, and who may use cookies, pixel tags and other technologies to serve and offer relevant ads.

Compliance and cooperation with regulatory authorities.

We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy. We also adhere to several self-regulatory frameworks. When we receive formal written complaints, we will contact the person who made the complaint to follow up. We work with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that we cannot resolve with our users directly.

CHANGES

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we may provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of privacy policy changes). The actual Privacy Policy for your review is placed on: **<http://semrush.com/privacy-policy/>**

CONTACT

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to us in writing at: SEMRUSH INC, **USA, 8 NESHAMINY INTERPLEX, STE 207, TREVOSE, PA 19053.**
